aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
What speed it has!
뭐가 저리 빠르담!?
That bastard!
이자식!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!!
Dag Fire!
다그 파이어!!
Fire Blaster!
파이어 블래스터!!
Big Panic of Insects
Space Birdman Garabird Seijin
Appears
Hmph... you're now asking me to move your things?
나 참.. 짐 운반까지 시키고 말야
Tell me what's inside.
뭐가 들어있는지 가르쳐줘
Alright, I'll tell you soon, so look forward to know!
알았어, 알았어~ 나중에 가르쳐 줄테니까 기대하고 있어
So what was this guy's objective?
결국 이녀석의 목적은 뭐였던 걸까?
I can't guess at all
짐작이 가질 않는군요
One thing sure is, that alien can fly faster than mach 8.
확실한건, 저 우주인의 비행속도는 마하 8 혹은 그 이상이라는 것
Yoku! I got you a present!
요쿠! 선물(Present) 가져왔어
Present?
선물?
-I found this in the park.
-I guess it's something plain.
-공원에서 발견했어
-어차피 변변찮은 물건이겠지
-What's this?
-Disgusting!
-뭐지, 이건?
-기분나뻐
This is terrific.
엄청나구만, 이거
Awesome!
대단해요!
This shape! This body! This is perfect, Gaku!
이 모습! 이 몸!
정말 대단합니다, 가쿠 군!
-Are you happy with this?
-Of course!
-마음에 들어?
-물론입니다!
Hey, you guys! Did you lost it?
잠깐, 너희들!
지금 제정신이야?!
Get rid of this thing right now!
이딴거, 얼른 갖다 버리라구!
-Agreed.
-Yeah.
-찬성
-음
Throw away? Nonsense! This is the discovery of the century!
버리다니, 말도 안되요! 이건 세기의 대 발견이라구요!
Is it an undiscovered new species, or a mutant from environmental destruction?
미지의 새로운 종(種)인가, 환경 파괴가 낳은 돌연변이인가
Anyway, we have to investigate about this.
아무튼 곰곰이 조사해 볼 필요가 있습니다
Would you like to do it together?
여러분도 함께 하실래요?
-I decline.
-Same for me.
-사양하겠다
-이하 동문
Instead, why not we sell it to a pet shop?
그것보다 말야, 애완동물 가게에 넘겨 버리자
-It'll worth a lot!
-Agreed!
-꽤 짭짤할 거라구
-찬성
You only think about small things...
아아.. 이 어찌 편협한 마음가짐이란 말인가...
You might won't understand, but this is a men's dream!
여러분은 이해 못할지도 모르겠지만 이건 남자의 로망입니다!
Getting a Ph. D. isn't considered a dream!
박사 학위도 꿈이 아닙니다!
Really... I am fed up with Yoku.
정말... 요쿠와는 같이 못 다니겠어
A youth spent with worms?
애벌레와 함께 보내는 청춘인가
I don't get it.
난 이해 못하겠어
Then, I'll go enjoy my youth with girls, so see ya!
그럼, 난 여자아이와 청춘을 보낼테니까, 먼저 갈게~
I am fed up with you too.
너하고도 같이 못 다니겠다
Then see you tomorrow!
그럼, 내일 보자
Huh? It's not there! It's gone!
아앗!? 없어! 없어졌어!
Did he do this?
이거, 그녀석의 짓?
Yoku!
요쿠!
Kai! This is bad!
카이! 큰일입니다!
That guy... that larva disappeared!
그녀석이, 그 애벌레가 없어요!
As expected.
역시 그런가
Anyway, follow me.
어쨌든, 어서 따라와
Sorry, but step aside.
미안, 좀 비켜줘
-What do you think?
-No doubt about it.
-어때?
-틀림없군요
That guy did it.
그녀석의 짓입니다
Anyway, it's terrific, for eating things like this too.
그건 그렇다 치고, 이런 것까지 먹어치우다니 굉장한 녀석이군요
Is this the time to be amazed?
감탄하고 있을 때냐?
You were supposed to take care of it from the first place!
애시당초 네가 제대로 관리를 하지 않으니까!
Anyway, let's scatter and find it before the damage becomes bigger.
어쨌든 피해가 커지기 전에 흩어져서 찾아보자
-What's up?
-We were changing our clothes and suddenly-
-무슨 일이지?
-오, 옷을 갈아입는데 갑자기!
A pervert?!
치한인가!?
Mo- monster!
괴, 괴물이!
Monster?!
괴물?!
That appetite...
이 식욕...
What the heck is inside its stomach?!
그녀석, 대체 위(胃)가 어떻게 돼먹은 거지?
Kai, look at this!
카이, 이걸 보세요!
What's that?
그건!?
-It looks like a cast-off skin.
-But what's up with that size?
-허물 같습니다
-하지만, 그 크기는?
Th- this size!
이, 이 크키는!?
You idiot!
바보녀석!!
That hurts!
아프구만~
What the heck was that?!
대체 무슨 일이야!?
Hey, look!
앗, 저기!
I can't believe my eyes!
마, 말도안돼!
It was only a single night and..
단 하룻밤만에 이렇게나!
-Let's go, Shin, Yoku!
-Alright!
-가자. 신, 요쿠!
-알았어!
-W- wait!
-Why?                 -Yoku!
-기, 기다려요!
-뭐?                  -요쿠!
This is a priceless creature!
이건 귀중한 생물입니다
Moreover, about the reason that how and why did it grow so quickly,
그리고 어째서 이렇게 빨리, 그것도 거대하게 성장한 것인가
we must investigate furthermore.
좀 더 자세하게 조사해 봐야...
Don't be unreasonable!
말도 안되는 소리 마!
Move away!
어서 비켜!
No!
싫어요!
Shadow Kunai!
섀도우 쿠나이!!
Ryu?!
류!?
You maniac! Are you trying to make us into its prey?!
이 오타쿠 자식아!
우리를 먹이로 만들 셈이냐!?
Bu- but!
하, 하지만...!
Heya!
이봐~
What are you doing in this place?
뭣들 하는 거야? 이런 곳에서
What were you doing until now?
너야말로 이런 시간까지 뭘 하고 있던 거야?
I- I'm not late or something!
지, 지각 같은거 안했어;;;
Put that aside! We got a trouble!
그런 것보다, 큰일이야!
Worm monsters has appeared!
괴물 애벌레가 나타났어!
Oh, about that, just now, at here...
아, 아.. 그거라면 방금 전에 여기에서...
No! It appeared in the village!
아니야! 마을에 나타났어!
There are tens of them creeping!
그것도 수십마리가 우글우글해!
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온!!
Fire En!
파이어 엔!!
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온!!
Turbo Kai!
터보 카이!!
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온!!
Armor Shin!
아머 신!!
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온!!
Wing Yoku!
윙 요쿠!!
Breast Motor Cannon!
브레스트 모터 캐논!!
Turbo Wheel Attack!
터보 호일 어택!!
Blizzard Hurricane!
블리자드 허리케인!!
Big Spiral Whirlwind Slash!
대회전 검풍참!!
He- help me!
사, 살려줘~
Fire Bird Attack!
파이어 버드 어택!!
Dagwon!
다그온!
There's no end to these!
이거, 끝이 없구만!
Where the heck are they coming out from?
대체 어디서 튀어나오는거야!?
A mutant made by environmental destruction.
환경 파괴가 낳은 돌연변이
This definitely is the warning of the mother nature to the humankind!
분명히 이건 인류에 대한 대자연의 경고입니다!
Then, we have only one way to settle this out!
그렇다면, 이 문제를 해결할 방법은 단 하나
We must capture them and find out the reason!
녀석들을 포획해서 원인을 규명하는 것 밖에는 없습니다!
Capture?!
포획!?
Hey, didn't you give up yet?!
너, 아직도 포기 안한거냐!?
They are not just a warning, but they are threat, no, natural enemy to the humankind!
녀석들은 경고 정도가 아니라 인류에게 있어 위협, 아니, 천적이라구!
Bu- but...
하, 하지만...
Look!
으음!? 저길 봐라!
Damn! Now an alien?!
제길! 우주인까지 나타난건가!?
-What the?!
-They're capturing the larvae!
-아니!?
-애벌레를 포획하고 있어요!
What's going on?
어떻게 된 거야?
They came again!
또 왔다!
What are they trying to do?
대체 무슨 목적으로?
No!
안돼!
Damn!
제길!
Yoku!
요쿠!!
You bastard!
이자식!
-Dammit!
-They ran away!
-제길!
-도망쳤군
Shin and I will go chase.
나와 신이 뒤를 쫓겠다
En, Ryu, you take care of the village!
엔과 류는 마을을 맡아줘
It can't be helped. I'll leave it to you guys this time.
할 수 없지, 이번엔 너희에게 맡길게
I wonder where is this heading to.
어디로 향하고 있는 걸까?
No...
아, 아무것도 아냐;;;
We'll get you!
놓치지 않는다!
What the?!
아니!?
Hmpt! You bird-headed!
칫! 이 닭머리 녀석!
Where is this?
여긴 어디지?
That's...
저건!?
Eggs?
알(卵)이군
That guy!
저녀석!
What the-?!
아니!?
Those larvae definitely are not the warning from the mother nature!
저 애벌레는 대자연의 경고 같은게 아니야
Those are nothing more than a food for that alien!
저녀석의... 우주인의 식량이었던 거야!
And its objective is...
그리고, 저녀석의 목적은...
to make the Earth to a farm!
지구를 목장으로 만드는 거였어!
But I won't let that happen!
하지만, 그렇게 내버려두진 않아!
Crystal Boomerang!
크리스탈 부메랑!!
N- no!
아, 아차!
-Yoku!
-Are you alright?
-요쿠!
-무사하냐!?
Ev- everyone!
여, 여러분!
It seems even bigger than before.
사, 상당히 건장해진 것 같은데?
But we'll take back Yoku, you bird-headed!
그래도, 요쿠는 되돌려 받겠다! 닭머리 자식아!
Final Buster!
파이널 버스터!!
-I- it's fast!
-And strong!
-빠, 빠르다!
-가, 강하다. 이녀석!
Incoming!
온다!
Only Dag Wing can match that speed!
저녀석의 스피드에 대항할 수 있는 건 다그 윙 밖에 없어!
Break Wheel!
브레이크 호일!!
Yoku!
요쿠!
Dag Turbo!
다그 터보!!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)!!
Dag Wing!
다그 윙!!
Here it goes!
간다!!
Crystal Cutter!
크리스탈 커터!!
Yoku, do not lose!
요쿠, 지지 마라!
Anything goes now!
이렇게 되면, 이판사판이다!
He did it!
-성공했다!
-해냈어!
-Now!
-Roger!
-지금입니다!
-오우!
Chaining Fusion!
중련합체(重連合體)!!
Liner Dagwon!
라이너 다그온!!
Liner Blizzard!
라이너 블리자드!!
Liner Tackle!
라이너 태클!!
Kai, Shin... thank you.
카이.. 신.. 고마워요
You made us worried one after another!
하나부터 열까지 걱정이나 끼치고 말야
We'll be paid back for your debt!
이 빚은 돌려받을테니까 말야
But anyway we managed to stop the alien's plan.
하지만, 우주인의 계획은 저지할 수 있었어
What a fortunate error.
전화위복(怪我の功名)인 셈이군
Yeah, but I am still concerned about something.
네, 하지만 한가지 마음에 걸리는게 있습니다
That larva... if it kept growing, what kind of adult insect it could have become?
그 애벌레... 그대로 성장을 계속 했다면 대체 어떤 성충이 되었을까요?
Y- you bastard! You didn't change at all!
이, 이자식! 전혀 반성 안했잖아! 이녀석!
Kai! Shin! Yoku! Hurry up and come back!
카이! 신! 요쿠! 빨리 돌아와줘!
There still are tons of worms to take care of!
애벌레는 아직 잔뜩 남아있다구!
Worm extermination again?!
또 애벌레 퇴치냐~!?
This will be all-night job.
오늘밤은 철야(徹夜 : 밤을 샘)겠군
Alright! I'll be able to make the sample of that space insect!
좋았어! 이걸로 우주 곤충의 표본을 만들 수 있어요!
Forget it!
너 말야!!
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
tooku kirameita
kaze no naka no PRISM
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
Killad Seijin absorbs the opponent's power to be strong.
상대의 힘을 흡수하여 힘을 늘려가는 키라드 성인
And in front of Ryu, one Tiger was sacrificed.
그리고 류의 눈 앞에서 한마리의 호랑이가 희생되었다
Ryu is burning with the will to revenge.
복수의 집념에 불타는 류
Killad Seijin is looking for that power and technique.
그 힘과 기술을 키라드 성인은 노리고 있다
Ryu! It's not just your fight!
류! 너 혼자만의 싸움이 아니라구!
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! Strength to my Hands
다음회 용자지령 다그온
힘을 나의 손에
A decisive battle is up ahead.
결전의 순간이 다가온다
Strength to my Hands
힘을 나의 손에